

Juan Pedro Grosso

Career Summary

Juan Pedro is a curious, hardworking, team person. He has obtained his PhD degree at UBA. On 2019 he was selected by Globant for the Big Data and AI studio. Work for a client, setting up an ORACLE-server with PYTHON, mounting a master-table and lunching a LightGBM model to replace an old regressionmodel for churn. Work in G-labs project (as a subject matter expert, biologist) to make a web-based tool to help plant breeders simulate plant crossings, infra in AWS. Work for a car manufacturer to make an absenteeism model, first with Facebook Prophet algorithm and after getting more data with a XGBOOST regressor its deployment in GCP.

Summary of Qualifications

Experienced In:

• R

ORACLSQL

Redhat

 SQLdevelop per

Jupyter-Notebook

PYTHON

Languages

Spanish (native speaker)

English (advanced)

French (advanced)

Career History

GLOBANT, CABA, Argentina

Data Scientist

August 2019 - Present

Apr. 2013 - Mar. 2018

UNIVERSIDAD de BUENOS AIRES, CABA, Argentina

PhD candidate

- Statistical analysis in R (data from various sources, clean, model and tested)
- Original research project (design, perform, analyse and present experiments, 1 peer review paper)
- Award CONICET PhD scholarship

Education

UNIVERSIDAD de BUENOS AIRES, CABA, Argentina

PhD in behavioral biology

Apr. 2013 - Mar. 2018

UNIVERSIDAD de BUENOS AIRES, CABA, Argentina

Bachelor in biology

Mar. 2007- Mar. 2013